A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Counsel's Office, Series 10 FA358
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Robert R. Douglass, 1959-1972; 3; 65 Document Box(es)
  - Politics - Program - Power-Public Service Commission (April 26-July 25, 1972) (Box 50, Folder 572)
    Correspondence; proposed bills; Proposed draft of resolution on Energy Policy for Governor's Conference; Program bill; Public Authority of the State of New York (PASNY) application to intervene in action by Federal Power Commission v. Greene County, et al.
  - Politics - Program - Power, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 573)
    Florida Gas Case; Public Service Commission (PSC) objection; NAR Press Release.
  - Politics - Program - Power, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 574)
    Public Service Commission Report on electric service adequacy in New York City area.
  - Politics - Program - Inaugural Address, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 575)
  - Politics - Program - Inaugural Address, 1971 (Box 50, Folder 576)
  - Politics - Program - Title XIX (Medical Expense Program for Needy Persons), 1966 (Box 50, Folder 577)
    Draft Legislation; memos; correspondence; Press Release.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1969-1970 (Box 50, Folder 578)
    Medicaid memos; 1969 program bills, correspondence; part of draft annual message.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 579)
    Medicaid memos.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 580)
    Medicaid, 1967 proposals.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 581)
    Medicaid and Public Assistance; Press Release and Bill.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 582)
    Welfare Reform Package; memoranda; correspondence; statistics.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 583)
    Welfare Administration Task Force; correspondence and creation of Task Force.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1971-1972 (Box 51, Folder 584)
    Medicaid - Title IV A and Title XVI. Memos and correspondence concerning the state fiscal crisis and the need to reduce Medicaid expenditures; memos on additional federal funding; contract between New York State Department of Social Services and New York State Narcotics Addiction Control Commission.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 585)
    Medicare - Title XIX Memos on "Responsible Relatives"; drafts of implementing legislation; correspondence; memos; Press releases; NAR TV program.
  - Politics - Program - Social Services, 1966-1971 (Box 51, Folder 586)
    Plan - Suffolk County - Expansion of Job Placement Program.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 587)
    Transcript of news conference April 20 on New Haven Railroad; Press Release NAR May 11.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1967 (Box 52, Folder 588)
    Transit Authority Negotiations; letter to Robert R. Douglass from the Public Employee Relations Board; Robert R. Douglass memo to NAR.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 589)
    Bill to allow State to provide money to New York City to maintain subway fare.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 590)
    Justice Saypool's decision finding pay raises to transit strikers illegal; Bill authorizing wage raises to Transit Workers to prevent strike renewal; Justice Hecht's decision holding Chapter 6 of the Laws of 1966 constitutional.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 591)
    Full Crew Repeal memo from M. Whiteman to Robert R. Douglass; copies of bills; status memos.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation - Long Island Bridges, 1967 (Box 52, Folder 592)
    Studies; news articles; polemics.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation - Metropolitan Commuter Transportation Authority (MCTA) Consolidation Bill, 1966-1967 (Box 52, Folder 593)
    Proposal to coordinate functions, powers and membership of Metropolitan Commuter Transportation Authority, New York City Transit Authority, and Triborough Bridge & Tunnel Authority; draft of proposed legislation and message (no action).
  - Politics - Program - Transportation - Plan for Aviation Needs, 1966-1967 (Box 52, Folder 594)
    Press Releases - additional jet port needed.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation - Freight Costs, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 595)
    Press Release - cutting costs.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation Bond Act, 1967 (Box 52, Folder 596)
    Drafts of Bills; Press Releases.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1970-1972 (Box 52, Folder 597)
    Hudson River Expressway; correspondence and memos.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation - Financing, 1970-1972 (Box 52, Folder 598)
    Regional - New York, Connecticut, New Jersey - Transportation; Press Releases, memos, correspondence.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1971-1972 (Box 52, Folder 599)
    Metropolitan Transit Authority (MTA): Correspondence (unpleasant) on audits of expenditures.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 600)
    Newburgh-Beacon Bridge. Correspondence on parallel bridge.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 601)
    Capital District Transportation Authority correspondence and memos on purchase of United Traction Company; audit and appraisal of United Traction Company.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1971-1972 (Box 53, Folder 602)
    Correspondence on Route 9A; State road programs 1971, 1972, 1973, 1974.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 603)
    File Plan note
    Richmond Parkway - background information; Mayor Lindsay "Recision of Approval"; Article 78 proceeding.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1971-1972 (Box 53, Folder 604)
    Stewart Airport expansion as jetport - local opposition.
  - Politics - Program - Transportation, 1971-1972 (Box 53, Folder 605)
    Niagara Frontier Transportation Authority; use of Federal Mass Transit monies.
  - Politics - Program - Veterans, 1967 (Box 53, Folder 606)
    Vietnam; Blind Annuity; Educational Assistance; leave of absence on Memorial & Veterans' Days; Qualification period; Scholar Incentive; State Scholarships for Children of Vets.
  - Politics - Program - Youth, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 607)
    Message material for 1965.
  - General Government - Office of Local Government - Temporary Commission Study, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 608)
    "Counties in New York" (Oct. 1969); "Public Authorities in New York" (Aug. 1971); "Special Improvement Districts in New York" (Aug. 1971); "Comprehensive Manpower Agency" (study: Sept, 1971); "Contracting-Out" (Sept. 1971); Temporary Commission: "Public-Private Sector Relations," "The Second Class Cities Law," and "Recodification of Statutes which cover local governments" (Oct. 1971).
  - General Government - Office of Local Government, October-December 1971 (Box 53, Folder 609)
    Memo on Revision of County Charter Law; correspondence on "streamlining" local government; first draft of "Reconnaissance Study" of Office of Local Government (OLG).
  - General Government - Office of Local Government, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 610)
    Memos on merger of Office of Local Government (OLG) and Equalization & Assessment; correspondence E&A; proposed Bill creating "Office of Planning and Local Government," Sal Prezioso letters to NAR; Interim Report on Powers of Local Government (Robert F. Wagner).
  - General Government - Pure Waters, 1970-1971 (Box 53, Folder 611)
    Correspondence; memos; reports; NAR testimony before House Public Works Committee (December 9, 1971); statements of Paul McCracken, Russell Train, William D. Ruckelshaus before House Public Works Committee; NAR letter to Chair (Blatnik) of House Public Works Committee; letter to NAR from Great Lakes Commission.
  - General Government - Pure Waters, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 612)
    Correspondence - withdrawal of 45 applications for Federal Grants for sewage treatment works; press release on halt in processing local applications; Statement to members of New York Congressional District.
  - General Government - Social Services Reorganization, 1969-1971 (Box 54, Folder 613)
    Memos, Studies, Correspondence, Legislative bills.
  - General Government, 1961-1963 (Box 54, Folder 614)
    Interstate Staff Committee - New Haven Railroad. Report of Staff Committee; Report to Governor and Legislature (March 6, 1961); Report of Staff Committee (February 15, 1963).
  - General Government, 1960-1964 (Box 54, Folder 615)
    Brochures: "The Government of New York STate"; "Meeting the Demand for Higher Education in New York State"; "The New York State and Local Tax System"; "Fallout Shelters"; "Youth Who Need Help"; "College Education (1961)"; "College Education 1963-1964"; "Significant Laws - 1963"; "New York State Services for its Older Citizens"; NAR speech May 2, 1963: "Building a Better Future for Older Persons."
  - General Government, 1963-1965 (Box 54, Folder 616)
    Tourism Guides and Maps.
  - General Government, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 617)
    New York State Brief before Interstate Commerce Commission on Railroad Consolidation: (1) Chesapeake & Ohio to Acquire Baltimore & Ohio; (2) New York Central to acquire Baltimore & Ohio.
  - General Government, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 618)
    New York State Commission on Governmental Operations of the City of New York - 1) A New Charter for the City of New York; 2) Proposed Cash, Investment and Debt Management Program for the City of New York.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 619)
    Parochial School Aid, March 25, 1971-May 10, 1971. Memos; draft legislation; comments on Bills.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also Folders 651-654.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 620)
    Parochial School Aid, May 12, 1971-September 1, 1971. Memos; draft legislation; analysis and comments on Bills.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 621)
    Parochial School Aid, Fall 1971. Memos; Report of President's Commission on School Finance.
  - General Government, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 622)
    Parochial School Aid, 1972. Program Bill; memos; correspondence; submissions by New York State Catholic Committee.
  - General Government, 1970-1972 (Box 55, Folder 623)
    Per Capital Aid Program - Report 1970, Press Release. Memo: Robert R. Douglass to Hurd & Dunham May 25, 1972.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 624)
    Railroad Real Property Tax Relief. Reports; memos; tables; letter to NAR from Sen. Griffin.
  - General Government, 1970-1971 (Box 55, Folder 625)
    Forum on National Priorities (University of the Pacific). News releases & press clippings.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 626)
    Railpax (National Rail Passenger Corporation) correspondence.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 627)
    Manpower Training Act Study (Feb. 1971); correspondence from Feb. 11 to March 26, 1971.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 628)
    Manpower Training Act Study. Reports and correspondence April 1971 to December 30, 1971.
  - General Government, 1972 (Box 56, Folder 629)
    Manpower Training Act, January-February 1972.
  - General Government, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 630)
    Rochester Bombings - correspondence; press releases.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 631)
    Regents Meeting. Press Release by Regents October 29, 1971 on governance of education in New York City; memo Robert R. Douglass to NAR; memo Robert R. Douglass to NAR on meeting December 16, 1971.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 632)
    Welfare Federal; Program Regulation; HR-1; Pamphlet: "Highlights of Welfare Reform."
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 633)
    Welfare Federal (February through March) Copy of City Brief in "City of New york, et. al. v. Richardson as Secretary of HEW, et al."; NAR letter to Wilbur Mills, correspondence, memos, Special Message by NAR to New York Legislature March 29, 1971.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 634)
    Welfare, Federal (April through July) Correspondence; telegram NAR to Wilbur Mills; memos; analysis of welfare reform bill; NAR speech to Associated Press Luncheon (April 19, 1971); Attorney General analysis of Housing Bill; Personal Incentive Program; Incentives for Independence.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 635)
    Welfare, Federal (August through September) Sen. Long's statement to Congress (July 27, 1971) on HR1; Demonstration Projects; Dept. of Social Services Analysis of HR1.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 636)
    Taylor Law - Program Bill for 1972; correspondence; drafts of bill.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 637)
    Tax Program 1971 Budget Bill Memorandum, Legislative Research memos.
  - General Government - Politics, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 638)
    Republican Governors' Association Meeting, December 1970. Background file; memos prior Governor's Association meetings.
  - General Government - Politics, 1971-1972 (Box 57, Folder 639)
    Speech File a) January 12, 1971 - New York State Women's Legislative Forum b) January 30, 1971 - New York State Bar Association Judiciary Committee c) February 15, 1971 - New York State Business & Professional Women's Clubs d) April 1971 - Response to WCBS-TV Editorial on Westside Highway Rebuilding e) July 8, 1971 - Dedication of Orange County Mental Health Center f) October 5, 1971 - Introduction of Indiana Governor Edgar Whitcomb at Great Leakes Commission. g) May 10, 1972 - American Society for Public Administration ("Change").
  - General Government - Politics, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 640)
    Speech File - NAR excerpts.
  - General Government - Politics, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 641)
    Speech File - Copies of others' speeches.
  - General Government - Politics, 1968 (Box 58, Folder 642)
    Speech 1968, First Annual Statewide Championship.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 643)
    Rent Control - memos; correspondence.
  - General Government, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 644)
    Rochester Clothing Industry.
  - General Government - Politics, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 645)
    Goldberg Press Releases.
  - General Government - Politics, January-February 1970 (Box 58, Folder 646)
    Political memos: suggestions of campaign strategy themes; campaign charges; background on Democratic candidates; Congressional races; Howard Samuel's programs; background on Richard Ottinger and Eugene Nickerson.
  - General Government - Politics, March-November 1970 (Box 58, Folder 647)
    Campaign suggestions; background on Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jr.; Samuels & Long Island Railroad; Goldberg positions; voting projections; Goldberg NAR debate & post-debate briefing papers; election projections.
  - General Government - Politics, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 648)
    Post-election reports.
  - General Government - United Fund Charity Drive, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 649)
  - General Government - Value Added Tax, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 650)
  - General Government - Parochial School Aid, 1971-1972 (Box 59, Folder 651)
    Confidential report (1971); correspondence; news articles; Illinois Report; copies of litigation papers in U.S. District Court, State University of New York.
    See also Folders 619-622.
  - General Government - Parochial School Aid, 1968-1969, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 652)
    (January through May 1971) Bill to halt busing; correspondence; reports; press releases; State of Maryland Report (1971); memos.
  - General Government - Parochial School Aid, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 653)
    (June through December 1971) correspondence; statement; proposed Bills; memos.
  - General Government - Parochial School Aid, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 654)
    Memos; correspondence; legal brief for repeal of Blaine Amendment.
  - General Government - Welfare Reorganization, March 1971 (Box 59, Folder 655)
    Correspondence and memos, NAR Special Message.
  - General Government - Welfare Reorganization, March 1971 (Box 59, Folder 656)
    Program outlines, Draft Legislation.
  - General Government - Welfare Reorganization, April-May 1971 (Box 60, Folder 657)
  - General Government - Welfare Reorganization, 1971 (Box 60, Folder 658)
    Correspondence; demo project application: Incentives for Independence Project.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign 1968 (55th Street Miscellaneous Files) (Box 60, Folder 659)
    Alabama, Arizona, California, Colorado, Delaware.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 660)
    Florida, Georgia, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 661)
    Kansas, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, Minnesota.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 662)
    Mississippi, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, New Mexico, New York.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 663)
    Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 664)
    South Carolina, Tennessee, Utah, Virgin Islands, Virginia, Washington, West Virginia, Wyoming.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 665)
    55th Street Miscellaneous Files, Malcolm Wilson.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 666)
    Women's Activities; Campaign Responsibilities, Campus Activities; Citizens Groups; Congratulations; Debate/Nixon (memo from Nancy Hanks).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 667)
    Douglass congratulations letters on appointment as campaign manager.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 668)
    John Deardourff; Executive Office for the President; finance committee; Lloyd Free; Jim Henderson; Sam Hausman activities; George Hinman; Emmet Hughes; Robert Kennedy assassination.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 669)
    Thomas Losee; miscellaneous correspondence A-K.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 670)
    Miscellaneous correspondence L-Z.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 671)
    National Bipartisan Movement, Inc.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 672)
    National committee; personal (Douglass).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 673)
    Press; Ronald Reagan; research.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 674)
    NAR schedules (May 19-June 12).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 675)
    Scheduling committee: objectives, organization and plans.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 676)
    To Leslie Slate; speech preparation materials; Steward Mott.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 677)
    Television interviews (how to conduct).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 678)
    "Thank you for your offer to help" letter responses.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 679)
    Tinker material (campaign material); Washington, DC, office.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 680)
    Schools and colleges.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 681)
    Personnel (includes Robert R. Douglass' first news conference as campaign manager on May 6).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 682)
    Speech material: public welfare; turmoil at Columbia University; Vietnam and world peace; general strategy; Robert Kennedy's career.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 683)
    Organization.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 684)
    Convention strategy memos; Fergus Reid files; Tom Stephens files; T. W. Braun report on campaign images.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 685)
    Delegate count ("Newsweek" magazine, March 1968).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 686)
    Delegate Operations Responsibility; News Clips; Delegate Procedure; Lloyd Free Report - Urban Problems; Headquarters.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 687)
    R. F. Kennedy Statements and Information.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 688)
    Office Procedure; Polls; Budget.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 689)
    Staff Documents - NAR Campaign Kit; Michigan Question & Answer Material.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 690)
    Staff Documents - NAR Campaign Kit; All NAR speeches to date (10); Rockefeller Campaign pamphlets (2); Press Releases (2).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 691)
    Domestic Policy Staff Notebook.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 692)
    Recommended Position Papers - Domestic Research Staff.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 693)
    Domestic Research Summary Position Papers.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 694)
    Briefing Book - Nixon.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 695)
    Schedule Books for June: Chicago; Wilmington; Sioux Falls, Huron; Little Rock.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 696)
    Schedule Books: Lincoln 6/28; Oklahoma City 6/28; San Antonio 6/29; Seattle 7/2.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 697)
    Schedule Books: Idaho 7/2; Oregon 7/3; Honolulu 7/5; Indiana 7/15.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 698)
    Schedule Books: Illinois 7/16; Wisconsin 7/17; Kansas 7/24.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 699)
    Memo from Richard Nathan on crime. Copy of "Seagram Spotlight" (article on Liberia).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 700)
    Survey: "Attitudes Towards Presidential Candidates" May 1968.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 701)
    Booklet: Governors of the American States; Commonwealths, and Territories 1968; Secretarial Notebook - untranscribed shorthand notes.
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 702)
    New York State Government Telephone Directory (6/10/67).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 703)
    Convention Book - guide to each state delegation hotel assignments; committee assignments; Schedules; State by state listing of Delegate Information (A-C).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 704)
    State Delegate Information (D-NH).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 705)
    States Delegate Information (NC to WY).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 706)
    Delegate Positions Book A-L (states).
  - General Government - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 707)
    Delegate Positions Book M-W (states).
  - General Government - 1966 Gubernatorial Campaign Archives Book (Box 64, Folder 708)
    Table of Contents; Director; New York City, Eugene T. Rossides; Jewish Press.
  - General Government - 1966 Gubernatorial Campaign Archives Book (Box 64, Folder 709)
    New York City, Gilbert A. Robinson; Canvasing; Treasurer; Finance Committee; Scheduling; Research; Special Groups; Constitutional Convention; Governor.
  - General Government - 1966 Gubernatorial Campaign Archives Book (Box 64, Folder 710)
    Public Relations and Press; PR O'Donnell; Citizens Committee; Literature; Miscellaneous; Photographs; Archives; Addenda; Index.
- Michael Whiteman, 1963-1974; 4; 80 Document Box(es)